<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blommaerts Edwin</title>
    <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blommaerts Edwin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 23:17:01 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blommaertsedwin.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cannibal Corpse</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/cannibalcorpse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 23:17:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/cannibalcorpse/</guid>
      <description>Such an epic evening. First we trash out to Municipal Waste and then we dive into Cannibal Corpse. To end the vening with an adventure with three other metal heads who couldn&amp;rsquo;t get to Stratford because of closed lines. Five busses and a car journey later we got home, otherwise it would have been an expensive cab journey home or a long wait for the train. Thanks again boys, you saved the night and it was epic getting to know you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Countdown</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/projects/countdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 22:14:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/projects/countdown/</guid>
      <description>Hi!
I created this countdown for you, it will show how many days, hours, minutes and seconds until your birthday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life and such</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/life-and-such/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 22:23:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/life-and-such/</guid>
      <description>Hello again fucked up world! This time I&amp;rsquo;m writing a positive message. I don&amp;rsquo;t know who will read this, and I don&amp;rsquo;t care. But the power of staying positive and not drowning yourself in sadness or self-pity is amazing. Just recently I was blown away by a series of positive events that all happened on the same day. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into details but at the end of the day, everything fell into place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petri dishes, vegies, and the kids story of the Koala, Panda and the Muppet.</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 23:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/life/</guid>
      <description>Hello fucked up world! Today I&amp;rsquo;m celebrating my one week of being a Vegetarian. Technically, pescetarian. I&amp;rsquo;ve not touched a single piece of meat since the start of the week. It&amp;rsquo;s been an interesting experience and it has been hard at times not to just give in. But hey, I&amp;rsquo;ve quit smoking, moved country, and pushed myself to a Uni degree while working in the past, so this is nothing, I don&amp;rsquo;t fear challenges!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22 Mile walk</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/22milewalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 09:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/22milewalk/</guid>
      <description>Empowered by Nirvana I went for a walk, got lost, and ended up doing 22 miles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nirvana Tribute</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/nirvana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 22:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/nirvana/</guid>
      <description>The scent of teen spirit lingered in the air on that crisp Saturday night. I was hesitant as I stepped into the venue, unsure of what to expect. The opening act left with a broken guitar, but then the Nirvana Tribute band took the stage. And let me tell you, they killed it. Song after song, they nailed it. I was stationed near the bar right in the center, the perfect spot to feel the energy pulsating through the crowd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long walk</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/30kwalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 21:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/30kwalk/</guid>
      <description>Went for a long walk today, and enjoyed myself. Listened to some music while walking and taking some good pictures and some bad ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UI Building and resource vs equipment data class</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 22:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/attack/</guid>
      <description>Started out wanting to add the attack mechanics but wound up switching to UI building. Specifically, building a character sheet with drag and drop for equipment.
Spend most of the time researching the best solution to build one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding inventory and item stacking</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/inventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/inventory/</guid>
      <description>After very little thought I went with Notion.so for my dev board. I&amp;rsquo;ve made the task Kanban board public so you can see but not edit it.
Today I&amp;rsquo;ve added an inventory screen with stackable items and item count. In the small video, you can see the max stack count is 5. So items can only be stacked up to 5 before a new stack is added to the inventory screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pancakes (With honey and sliced apples)</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 15:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Extra dad points for me today, managed to speed-cook pancakes with honey and sliced apples. All within the time I have allowed myself to pick her up from school and then make her a snack. Happy kid, happy life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poppedecorn!</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/popedecorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 20:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/popedecorn/</guid>
      <description>Today I introduced my daughter to the popcorn song! We both danced, we put it on repeat, slammed a bag of popcorn in the microwave, and danced some more. She&amp;rsquo;s now eaten a small bowl of popcorn.
I love my life and my daughter.
I ended it with a METAL VERSION!!!!! \m/
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding the attacking animation</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/addingattacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 21:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/addingattacking/</guid>
      <description>While listening to Sir Patrick Steward divulge his memoir on Spotify. I hack away at my silly game.
Firstly I need to key in the attacking animation for each direction. This was fairly easy as it just meant adjusting hr Frame Coords. Next, I&amp;rsquo;m going to hook these animations in the Left Mouse button click. which again was fairly easy as I captured the input and gave a signal to the State Machine to travel to the attack state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lets go with some more integrating of the animations</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/somemoregamedev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 21:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/somemoregamedev/</guid>
      <description>Right, made some more progress with the animation tree and hooking that into the state machine. I would also need a place to store ideas and tasks I need to work on. I&amp;rsquo;ve got the character in a decent state but there are a few improvements I would like to add, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with that just yet. So some sort of list would be nice.
I had to register if the right mouse button was held down as a separate variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Sprite Sheets and the wonderful combo of State Charts and movement.</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/animatethecharacterparttwo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/animatethecharacterparttwo/</guid>
      <description>Cracking on with the game. Looks like the pre-generated code for a CharacterBody2d is actually for a side scroller. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll use a state machine for the player character so we can control animations or other game functions by looking at what state the character is in.
I&amp;rsquo;ve done some research since my last post. I&amp;rsquo;ve come across this StateChart plugin for Godot. I thought it might be handy for my players and enemies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Git plugin for Godot4 on Linux and animating a character</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/makesomeprogress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 15:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/makesomeprogress/</guid>
      <description>Right, time to crack on with this characters. I&amp;rsquo;ve loaded the sprite sheet into the Sprite2D node by dragging it over the Texture field. Now it&amp;rsquo;s a matter of figuring out how many H- and Vframes are in the animation, additionally, I need to figure out the frame coordinates.
I set the Scale to x 1 and y 1 but to do this I had to unlink them, then set the values then relink them again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picking up Godot4 again</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/pickingupagain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 01:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/pickingupagain/</guid>
      <description>Starting over    New beginings    With the help of my previously written code, I&amp;rsquo;m starting over. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to just take my old project and build on that. I think it&amp;rsquo;s better to pick the good bits out of what I&amp;rsquo;ve written already. I&amp;rsquo;d like to make it more modular so I can share this with other communities.
Character    Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the main character and since the main character is called Little Death let&amp;rsquo;s make it a skeleton.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live review: Lord Of The Lost, 23-09-23, London, UK</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/lordofthelost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 22:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/lordofthelost/</guid>
      <description>After a long train journey in which I drained my phone battery to about 36%, I arrived about an hour early at the O2 Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s Bush Empire venue and was surprised to find a sloppy long winding queue in an alley down the side of the building. With some difficulty, I was able to find where I could join in. The weather was crisp but not cold and there was a nice atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year!</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/itisthenewyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/itisthenewyear/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new year. Let&amp;rsquo;s create a new list.
 Keep running, and initially run more than I did last year. Looking at the stats on Strava that would mean running more than 292.3 km, which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be hard to do. If I succeed with that I&amp;rsquo;ll try and go for 1000km for 2024. Write about my experience going through this journey. Last year&amp;rsquo;s (2023) stats:  Activities 56 Distance 292.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost the new year</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/almostthenyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 22:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/almostthenyear/</guid>
      <description>Well, what a year this has been. My daughter turned six. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe how fast she&amp;rsquo;s growing. I can still vividly remember being able to hold her in one arm, the palm of my hand cradling her little head. Now she&amp;rsquo;s putting on children&amp;rsquo;s makeup and talking about boys that kissed her.
I&amp;rsquo;m now also single. I didn&amp;rsquo;t see that one coming at the start of the year, but here we are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pervy man needs more stuff to hide behind</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-seventh-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 02:26:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-seventh-post/</guid>
      <description>Using my partner&amp;rsquo;s Wacom Bamboo drawing pad, I went to work creating some bushes and a palisade, also known as a stake wall. At first, I used GIMP, and would make a drawing and then convert it to pixel art. That did not work well as the Jpeg came out all blurred. I then decided to use a program I had purchased a long time ago called Aseprite. After watching a few Youtube videos and picking up some hints and tips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I created a Tree!</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-sixth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-sixth-post/</guid>
      <description>I was tired of seeing my little man running around stark naked without anywhere to hide behind. So I created a tree for him. Using Y-sort, collision shapes, and static bodies, I made it possible for him to go behind the tree but not go through it.
Behold my creation!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Added a start menu placeholder to my game</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-fifth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 02:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-fifth-post/</guid>
      <description>As part of my do something every day, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a quick placeholder start screen of my game. Here is my little Frankenstein&amp;rsquo;s monster and, just like its name partner, it is ugly to look at but, it is alive!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New year, new beginings</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 17:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-third-post/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get the new year off to a good start with some personal goals:
 Get back into running, with the goal being, getting back to where I was two years ago. I want to run 5k in under 30 minutes and run 21k. I want to make progress on my game project EVERY DAY, as small or as big and, whatever it is, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s something. Have a finished game by the end of the year, playable with a game loop, published, and asking feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing tabletop RPG with the boys.</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:27:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-second-post/</guid>
      <description>I thoroughly enjoyed gaming with my friends today. Even though I was pretty tired and had a head full of worries, just hearing them laugh and enjoy the game I was running for them cheered me up. The only thing missing to improve the atmosphere was some music and sound effects. I plan to add this to the next session by using a discord bot and Syrinscape. Additionally, I have a few ideas that I would like to try out in terms of the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:10:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/about/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G(odot) U(nit) T(esting) and Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:27:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I had previously already added unit tests to my game. There&amp;rsquo;s already a fair few youtube videos and guides out there describing how to do this. What I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of is that it is actually particularly easy to setup godot automated testing (GUT) upon pushing code into github using github actions.
 Log into you github account and create a new action workflow.    Then add the following at the bottom of the blank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dungeon Delver</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/projects/dungeon_delver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 03:10:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/projects/dungeon_delver/</guid>
      <description>What is Dungeon Delver?    Some time ago I was introduced to Godot by a colleague. Godot is an Open Source game engine with the built-in scripting language GDscript being very similar to Python. Over a weekend, I decided to download the engine and give it a go. I enjoyed how the engine structures components and how there is a friendly community surrounding it. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before I had the idea of building a top-down action role-playing game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Curse Of Strahd</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/projects/dnd_curse_of_strahd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 03:10:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/projects/dnd_curse_of_strahd/</guid>
      <description>What is Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons: Curse Of Strahd?    It is a D&amp;amp;D tabletop RPG game, it is me and some long terms friends who roll some dice and act out various characters going through an adventure together. We do stupid and silly stuff, drink a few beers and enjoy ourselves. We decided to record it and just share it with everyone interested. I know there&amp;rsquo;s still a taboo and stigma that hangs around playing these types of games.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
