<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blommaerts Edwin</title>
    <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blommaerts Edwin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 17:40:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blommaertsedwin.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New year, new beginings</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 17:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-third-post/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get the new year off to a good start with some personal goals:
 Get back into running, with the goal being, getting back to where I was two years ago. I want to run 5k in under 30 minutes and run 21k. I want to make progress on my game project EVERY DAY, as small or as big and, whatever it is, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s something. Have a finished game by the end of the year, playable with a game loop, published, and asking feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing tabletop RPG with the boys.</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:27:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-second-post/</guid>
      <description>I thoroughly enjoyed gaming with my friends today. Even though I was pretty tired and had a head full of worries, just hearing them laugh and enjoy the game I was running for them cheered me up. The only thing missing to improve the atmosphere was some music and sound effects. I plan to add this to the next session by using a discord bot and Syrinscape. Additionally, I have a few ideas that I would like to try out in terms of the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:13:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:10:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/about/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G(odot) U(nit) T(esting) and Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:27:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I had previously already added unit tests to my game. There&amp;rsquo;s already a fair few youtube videos and guides out there describing how to do this. What I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of is that it is actually particularly easy to setup godot automated testing (GUT) upon pushing code into github using github actions.
 Log into you github account and create a new action workflow.    Then add the following at the bottom of the blank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact_me</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/contact/contact_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 03:27:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/contact/contact_me/</guid>
      <description>WIP</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dungeon Delver</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/projects/dungeon_delver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 03:10:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/projects/dungeon_delver/</guid>
      <description>What is Dungeon Delver?    Some time ago I was introduced to Godot by a colleague. Godot is an Open Source game engine with the built-in scripting language GDscript being very similar to Python. Over a weekend, I decided to download the engine and give it a go. I enjoyed how the engine structures components and how there is a friendly community surrounding it. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before I had the idea of building a top-down action role-playing game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Curse Of Strahd</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/projects/dnd_curse_of_strahd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 03:10:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/projects/dnd_curse_of_strahd/</guid>
      <description>What is Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons: Curse Of Strahd?    It is a D&amp;amp;D tabletop RPG game, it is me and some long terms friends who roll some dice and act out various characters going through an adventure together. We do stupid and silly stuff, drink a few beers and enjoy ourselves. We decided to record it and just share it with everyone interested. I know there&amp;rsquo;s still a taboo and stigma that hangs around playing these types of games.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
