<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>me on Blommaerts Edwin</title>
    <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/authors/me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in me on Blommaerts Edwin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 13:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blommaertsedwin.io/authors/me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Very surprised by solo RPG Ironswon.</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-fourth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 13:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-fourth-post/</guid>
      <description>This is the IronlandsThe gods are many; magic is rare and dangerous. Monstrous beasts stalk the wild areas, but they can be tamed. In these lands when one lays their hand on iron and they swear into their soul it becomes a vow of solemn determination treated with the utmost gravity. The Ironsworn make a living of it. Powerful, travelled, and often gifted with magic, they journey as they please, finding those who are seeking help, or perhaps in service to their own needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing tabletop RPG with the boys.</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:27:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-second-post/</guid>
      <description>I thoroughly enjoyed gaming with my friends today. Even though I was pretty tired and had a head full of worries, just hearing them laugh and enjoy the game I was running for them cheered me up. The only thing missing to improve the atmosphere was some music and sound effects. I plan to add this to the next session by using a discord bot and Syrinscape. Additionally, I have a few ideas that I would like to try out in terms of the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G(odot) U(nit) T(esting) and Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:27:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I had previously already added unit tests to my game. There&amp;rsquo;s already a fair few youtube videos and guides out there describing how to do this. What I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of is that it is actually particularly easy to setup godot automated testing (GUT) upon pushing code into github using github actions.
 Log into you github account and create a new action workflow.    Then add the following at the bottom of the blank.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
