<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>me on Blommaerts Edwin</title>
    <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/authors/me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in me on Blommaerts Edwin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 22:08:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blommaertsedwin.io/authors/me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Live review: Lord Of The Lost, 23-09-23, London, UK</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/lordofthelost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 22:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/lordofthelost/</guid>
      <description>After a long train journey in which I drained my phone battery to about 36%, I arrived about an hour early at the O2 Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s Bush Empire venue and was surprised to find a sloppy long winding queue in an alley down the side of the building. With some difficulty, I was able to find where I could join in. The weather was crisp but not cold and there was a nice atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year!</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/itisthenewyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/itisthenewyear/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new year. Let&amp;rsquo;s create a new list.
 Keep running, and initially run more than I did last year. Looking at the stats on Strava that would mean running more than 292.3 km, which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be hard to do. If I succeed with that I&amp;rsquo;ll try and go for 1000km for 2024. Write about my experience going through this journey. Last year&amp;rsquo;s (2023) stats:  Activities 56 Distance 292.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost the new year</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/almostthenyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 22:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/almostthenyear/</guid>
      <description>Well, what a year this has been. My daughter turned six. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe how fast she&amp;rsquo;s growing. I can still vividly remember being able to hold her in one arm, the palm of my hand cradling her little head. Now she&amp;rsquo;s putting on children&amp;rsquo;s makeup and talking about boys that kissed her.
I&amp;rsquo;m now also single. I didn&amp;rsquo;t see that one coming at the start of the year, but here we are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pervy man needs more stuff to hide behind</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-seventh-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 02:26:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-seventh-post/</guid>
      <description>Using my partner&amp;rsquo;s Wacom Bamboo drawing pad, I went to work creating some bushes and a palisade, also known as a stake wall. At first, I used GIMP, and would make a drawing and then convert it to pixel art. That did not work well as the Jpeg came out all blurred. I then decided to use a program I had purchased a long time ago called Aseprite. After watching a few Youtube videos and picking up some hints and tips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I created a Tree!</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-sixth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-sixth-post/</guid>
      <description>I was tired of seeing my little man running around stark naked without anywhere to hide behind. So I created a tree for him. Using Y-sort, collision shapes, and static bodies, I made it possible for him to go behind the tree but not go through it.
Behold my creation!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Added a start menu placeholder to my game</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-fifth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 02:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-fifth-post/</guid>
      <description>As part of my do something every day, I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a quick placeholder start screen of my game. Here is my little Frankenstein&amp;rsquo;s monster and, just like its name partner, it is ugly to look at but, it is alive!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New year, new beginings</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 17:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-third-post/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get the new year off to a good start with some personal goals:
 Get back into running, with the goal being, getting back to where I was two years ago. I want to run 5k in under 30 minutes and run 21k. I want to make progress on my game project EVERY DAY, as small or as big and, whatever it is, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s something. Have a finished game by the end of the year, playable with a game loop, published, and asking feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing tabletop RPG with the boys.</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:27:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-second-post/</guid>
      <description>I thoroughly enjoyed gaming with my friends today. Even though I was pretty tired and had a head full of worries, just hearing them laugh and enjoy the game I was running for them cheered me up. The only thing missing to improve the atmosphere was some music and sound effects. I plan to add this to the next session by using a discord bot and Syrinscape. Additionally, I have a few ideas that I would like to try out in terms of the story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G(odot) U(nit) T(esting) and Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:27:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I had previously already added unit tests to my game. There&amp;rsquo;s already a fair few youtube videos and guides out there describing how to do this. What I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of is that it is actually particularly easy to setup godot automated testing (GUT) upon pushing code into github using github actions.
 Log into you github account and create a new action workflow.    Then add the following at the bottom of the blank.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
