<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life on Blommaerts Edwin</title>
    <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on Blommaerts Edwin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 15:38:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blommaertsedwin.io/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pancakes (With honey and sliced apples)</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 15:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Extra dad points for me today, managed to speed-cook pancakes with honey and sliced apples. All within the time I have allowed myself to pick her up from school and then make her a snack. Happy kid, happy life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poppedecorn!</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/popedecorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 20:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/popedecorn/</guid>
      <description>Today I introduced my daughter to the popcorn song! We both danced, we put it on repeat, slammed a bag of popcorn in the microwave, and danced some more. She&amp;rsquo;s now eaten a small bowl of popcorn.
I love my life and my daughter.
I ended it with a METAL VERSION!!!!! \m/
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live review: Lord Of The Lost, 23-09-23, London, UK</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/lordofthelost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 22:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/lordofthelost/</guid>
      <description>After a long train journey in which I drained my phone battery to about 36%, I arrived about an hour early at the O2 Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s Bush Empire venue and was surprised to find a sloppy long winding queue in an alley down the side of the building. With some difficulty, I was able to find where I could join in. The weather was crisp but not cold and there was a nice atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year!</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/itisthenewyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 18:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/itisthenewyear/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new year. Let&amp;rsquo;s create a new list.
 Keep running, and initially run more than I did last year. Looking at the stats on Strava that would mean running more than 292.3 km, which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be hard to do. If I succeed with that I&amp;rsquo;ll try and go for 1000km for 2024. Write about my experience going through this journey. Last year&amp;rsquo;s (2023) stats:  Activities 56 Distance 292.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost the new year</title>
      <link>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/almostthenyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 22:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blommaertsedwin.io/posts/almostthenyear/</guid>
      <description>Well, what a year this has been. My daughter turned six. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe how fast she&amp;rsquo;s growing. I can still vividly remember being able to hold her in one arm, the palm of my hand cradling her little head. Now she&amp;rsquo;s putting on children&amp;rsquo;s makeup and talking about boys that kissed her.
I&amp;rsquo;m now also single. I didn&amp;rsquo;t see that one coming at the start of the year, but here we are.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
